Inventory of the Lottie V. Clark Papers 1849-1915
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Lottie V. Clark Papers, 1849, 1888-1898, 1915, n.d.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 C54
123 items.
Papers, 1849, 1888-1899, 1915, of members of the Clark family of Amelia County, Virginia including letters, 1888-1895, written to Lottie V. Clark by Anthelia Holt who ran looms in a cotton textile factory in Chesterfield County, Virginia; and letters addressed to Martha Susan Clark and Missouri A. Clark.
Lottie V. Clark,; Martha S. Clark,; Missourie A. Clark.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 120 items, 6 March 1940
Gift: 3 items, 31 March 1998
Scope and Content Information
Papers of members of the Clark family of Amelia County, Virginia, dated 1849, 1889-1899, 1915. The collection consists primarily of letters written to Lottie V. Clark of Namozine, Amelia County, Virginia, by Anthelia Holt and other friends in Chesterfield County, Virginia, which discuss social, religious, and family matters, and Anthelia's work in a cotton mill. In addition, there are letters, invitations, and poems, 1849, 1890, and n.d., addressed to Martha Susan Clark and Missouri A. Clark; and Amelia County subpoena, n.d.; and two later business letters.
Arrangement
Organization
Organized into 3 series: Series 1. Lottie V. Clark correspondence; Series 2. Martha S. Clark and Missouri A. Clark correspondence; Series 3. Miscellaneous.
Arrangement
All series are arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Cotton textile industry -- Southern States.; Women -- Virginia--History -- 19th century.; Women-- Virginia -- Social life and customs.
Geographical name:
Amelia County (Va.) --History -- 19th century.
Persons:
Clark, Lottie V., fl. 1888-1895.; Clark, Martha Susan.; Clark, Missouri A.
Contents List
  Series 1: Lottie V. Clark correspondence
- Lottie V. Clark correspondence, 1888-1895. (Box-folder 1:1-5 and 2:1-3)
  chronological
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 18 July 1888., 4 pp. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Describes in detail church "feast" where young women made matching ties and aprons, and young men had to find the young woman with an apron to match their tie; also describes upcoming social events.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to "My Dear Little Friend," [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 15 August 1888., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Reports that an aunt and a cousin have died, and that there is a great deal of sickness; hopes to go up to the country in September.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca P.O., Chesterfield County, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 17 October 1888., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Has just returned from Crewe,[Virginia] and has been going to church every night; discusses upcoming marriages and waiting on a couple; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to "Dear Little Friend," [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 21 November 1888., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Begs her "Dear Little Friend" to visit her for Christmas, and describes the festivities planned; sends congratulations to her Uncle Dibbrel on his upcoming marriage.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca P.O., [Virginia], to Lottie V. Clark, Namozine P.O., [Virginia], 14 December 1888., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Describes upcoming social events; reports that she received a present of the book David Copperfield from a young man in Richmond; describes in detail her "winter suit."
  - Anthelia [Holt), Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 2 January 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Complains of having a bad cold; discusses what a nice Christmas she had--"I never saw a single person drunk nor heard a single biddle"; sends greetings to various family members.
  - "Annie," Anthelia T.[?] Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 15 February 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Describes several outings with various young men; says she will be "coming up to Trinity Church one Sunday before long" and asks Lottie to meet her.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 25 March 1889., 1 p. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Asks why she has not written; describes a visit to the country; sends greetings to other members of her family. 3 pp. ALS. Including a list of young women's names.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to "Dear Friend," [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 26 April 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Describes her "holliday" spent in the country, including having five young men want to take her to church; gives details of an elopement and of a marrage between a sixty-five year old man and a young girl.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 27 May 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Discusses the visit of a friend, Nora, who has made a "mash--he called tonight and is here now"; plans to visit in August; says she heard about the "mash he [Lottie's Uncle Junius] made week before last--tell him that he must not get married before I come up."
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 17 July 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Complains of feeling poorly for several weeks; describes a five week work stoppage at the mill due to high water; gives details of the fourth of July picnic.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to "Dearest Little Friend " [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 11 August 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Discusses upcoming picnic; describes a double wedding she attended; asks about Lottie's Uncle Junius and Dibbrel's wedding plans.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 13 September 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Talk of the mill stopping; talks about church meetings and upcoming marriages.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia]., 31 [sic][30] September 1889., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    Disappointed to report the mill did not step, and she is working until after seven o'clock every night, and on Saturday until four; describes a wedding between an "old widdow and an old widdower."
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 1 January 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Describes Christmas festivities; asks about her new brother; sends pictures of herself.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia]., 5 February 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Wants to know if the pictures arrived and why she has not written; reports that she has been ill with the flu ("grippe").
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 28 February 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Expresses the desire to attend school, and is happy that Lottie is able to go to school; describes the school and the new preacher.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 14 March 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Expresses sympathy at the death of Charlie [Lottie's cousin?]; says she is happy to be working ten hours again so that she is home by five o'clock; says that she must stay up with one of her cousin's little girls who was badly burnt.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 11 April 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Has been caring for a cousin sick with pneumonia; went fishing over her holiday; asks about April Fool's Day.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 2 May 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Asks about "trying fortune" on May 1; glad to hear Lottie's uncles are now in charge of the post office; talks about the "protractedi?] meeting" on Sunday and other church services.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 25 May 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Describes the "gracious revivial" with "one hundred converts"; asks about Uncle Dibbrel's wedding plans.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 18 July 1890., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Reports the sad news that her oldest brother has been killed in a railroad accident.
  - Anthelia [Hoit], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 18 August 1890., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Is working half-time and would like to come up for a visit.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, to "My Dear Friend [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 29 April 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Describes a recent wedding; talks of the "protracted[?] meeting" at church.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to "Dear Friend " [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 20 May 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Reports on sickness and recent deaths in the area.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 23 June 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Thanks Lottie for showing her such a good time during her visit; expresses dismay that Mr. Bridgewater, whose "wife was buried just five weeks ago," is getting married next week.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, to "Ever Dear Friend " [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 5 July 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Complains of feeling sick; discusses the young men at various sociai events, and states that she "would not give the snap of my finger for all the men I saw yesterday--if I can't see the one I want to see I don't care to see anyone"; describes a new dress and some quilts she is making.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to "My Own Darling," [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 12 July 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Reports that. Lottie's Uncle Scott and grandfather have been to Matoaca for a visit; discusses mutual friends and acquaintances.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 28 July 1891., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Happy to hear she is coming for a visit; talks about making wine and apple cider.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 11 August 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Talks of "feast" Saturday night and "childrens day"; asks about camp meeting; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 18 August 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Talks of working on her quilt and being teased about plans to marry; tells of upcoming church picnic; sorry to hear of illness of Lottie's yrandfather.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to "My Dearest Friend" [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 31 August 1891., 8 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Happy to have received Lottie's picture; sends condolences on death of Lottie's grandfather; discusses mutual friends; talks about running five to six looms at the mill.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 24 September 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Has quilted two quilts, and has two more to quilt; is getting ready for the fair in Richmond.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia]., 4 October 1891., 8 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Complains of being sick; hopes that she and her family have decided to become Christians following the meeting; discusses the weekend events; is sending a scrapbook to her; glad to hear of several people who had joined the church.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to "Dearest Friend," [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 1 November 1891., 6 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Discusses managing the household while her parents were gone; describes the fair [in Richmond]; describes a shopping trip to Petersburg; reports that a cousin has died; probably will not be able to visit at Christmas.
  - Susie M. Eudaily [Drakes Branch, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 6 November 1891., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Hopes to visit again soon; discusses a recent marriage and baptizing.
  - Susie M. Eudaily, [Drakes Branch, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 26 November 1891., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Complains of everyone having colds; hopes to visit at Christmas time.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 28 November 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Has been running six looms at the mill; invites her down for Christmas; describes a quilting with "plenty of music and singing"; says they have plenty of meat now that "Pa" has had his hogs killed.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 22 December 1891., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Reports that their mail carrier has died; says there is a lot of sickness; hopes Lottie will enjoy the "Sugar Stew."
  - Anthelia [Holt], [Matoaca, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 10 January 1892., 6 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Everyone has been sick; describes Christmas and the many visitors.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 4 February 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Describes a candy party; complains that she "was disappointed last Saturday and Sunday my fellow did not come"; has been making pillow cases.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Eva.], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 14 February 1892., 8 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Reports they have a lot of sickness; the tinners have been tinning their house; her "fellow" came by on Sunday; describes a wedding that "did not come off."
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca. [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 25 February 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Had to work until seven o'clock; went to church the night before and heard a "beautiful sermon"; hopes to be able "to go up in Chesterfieid, " [Virginia] for the weekend.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Eva.], to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 2 March 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Writes that she is sorry to hear that Lottie's Uncle [Dibbrel] was burned; complains of a lot of sickness; describes a party in the country.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 8 March 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Describes purchases from a trip to town; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 21 March 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Describes a tripto country; claims she will never marry as "my fellow has gone back on me"; invites her down for the "protracted[?] meeting"; plans to visit her if the mill stops during the summer; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 11 April 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Complains of feeling ill; talks of recent and upcoming marriages.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 19 April 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Has been sick all week; asks about various friends and family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 25 April 1892., ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Reports that a cousin, Willie Holt, has died, possibly from typhoid fever; talks of the church meeting and the converts they have had.
  - Susie M. Eudaily, [Drakes Branch, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 22 May 1892., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Sends best wishes to "the bride ang [sic] groom" [Lottie's uncle and his wife]; is afraid she will not be able to visit in the summer.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to "My Darling " [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 7 June 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Describes a weekend in the country; claims that her Uncle Edd was "craisy with whiskey when Willie died" but he has gotten better now; talks of mutual friends.
  - Anthelia [Holt), Matoaca, [Virginia], to "My Dear Friend "[Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 23 June 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Has been busy with a sick friend who died of "conjestion [sic] on the brain"; invites her down for the 4th of July.
  - Susie M. Eudaily, Drakes Branch, Charlotte County, Virginia, to Lottie V. Clarke [sic], Namozine, Amelia CO., Virginia, 29 June 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Both she and her family have been very sick.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to "My Dear Friend," [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia]., 14 July 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Describes the Fourth of July picnics and all the company they have had.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Manchester, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 19 August 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Has been sick and unable to work, so has gone to stay with a cousin; asks about friends and family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 12 September 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Went to a picnic and had a splendid time, but upon her return learned that a cousin had been killed at the railroad; would like to quit working at the mill; sends greetings to various fmaily members.
  - Susie [M.] E[udaily, Drakes Branch, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine,Virginia], 12 September 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Talks about the church meeting and the 90 conversions; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Susie [M.] Eudaily, [Drakes Branch, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 29 September 1892., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Discusses mutual friends.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 4 October 1892., 6 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Reports there is much sickness and death in the area; asks about Lottie's new beau; talks about the three fellows she and her two sisters[?] go around with; plans on quilting a new quilt.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 5 December 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Describes visit of friends from Petersburg, [Virginia]; talks of upcoming marriages; invites her and her family down for Christmas.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 25 December 1892., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Describes the many visitors and social events that have kept her busy; gives details of a wedding; talks of various young men; reports that a cousin has died, "I never felt as sorry for any boddy [sic] in my life as I did for his sweetheart--it seemed like her heart would break when she looked at him for the last time"; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie (V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 10 January 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Complains of being lonely since her visit; plans to come up and visit; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 20 January 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Describes a "sugar stew--I stewed the sugar Wednesday night and pulled it and last night she had her party"; complains of the snow and cold; discusses an upcoming wedding.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 7 February 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Describes various parties and a wedding; hopes to visit her in two weeks if Uncle [Dibbrel] can come and get her.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, [Virginia], to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 20 March 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Invites her down for Easter; describes a wedding where "the bridegroom was so drunk that he could hardly stand up"; has been working on "another bed quilt."
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 28 March 1893., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Has been suffering from a toothache; has been able to find someone to take over her looms at the mill, and so will be able to visit.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to [Lottie V. Clark, Narnozine, Virginia], 29 April 1893., 8 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Reports that she ate some raisins that made her sick; describes several weddings; describes her sister's "fellow--his head is red as fire and he is real good looking."
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie V. Clarke [sic], Namozine, Virginia, 15 May 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Complains that she has not written in weeks; describes the revival meeting going on at church.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 2 July 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Has been busy making a dress, entertaining company, and going to a lawn party; is angry that she did not stop for a visit while in Petersburg, [Virginia]; invites Lottie down for the Fourth of July picnics.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Narnozine, Virginia], 21 July 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Had to have a tooth taken out; has been running six looms a day; reports there has been a lot of sickness and death in the area.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 21 August 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Is having a good time since the mill shut down; went to see a "game of baseball"; plans to go up the river for a fish fry; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 21 September 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Talks about several quilts she is working On; claims that she will never marry despite the "widdowers [sic]...that wants to wait on me"; asks about a shooting; complains that they can only work half-time; plans to visit next year.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 2 October 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Reports there is a lot of sickness in the area; spent several days in the country with relatives; claims she is kept busy entertaining the widowers; talks of the church meeting that has lasted several weeks.
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 1 December 1893., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Has been to several Christmas parties already this year; discusses the widowers who are courting her; invites her down for Christmas; discusses an upcoming marriage--"hard times don't keep people from geting [sic] married."
  - Anthelia [Holt], [Matoaca, Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 14 December 1893., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Discusses the festivities planned for Christmas; work has started up full-time again; claims she will "marry the very next" widower who asks.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 16 January 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Reports that her parents are sick with "la grippe" (flu); claims that her fellow was at the mill on Sunday, but has left for Georgia.
  - "Cousin," Grace [?], Drewrys Bluff, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 17 January 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)